<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Image Resizer Online Blog</title>
    <link>https://imageresizer.online/blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Image Resizer Online Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 13:39:48 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://imageresizer.online/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Image Format for the Web</title>
      <link>https://imageresizer.online/blog/posts/best-image-format-for-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 13:39:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imageresizer.online/blog/posts/best-image-format-for-the-web/</guid>
      <description>JPEG JPEG is a widely used image format. One of its strengths is its compatibility. Pretty everything can use JPEG.
There are many tools that allow you to compress JPEG files, one of those tools is ImageResizer.online. It makes resizing images easy on the web with no need to upload files to a server so it is secure and very fast.
Pros:  small file size able to easily change the quality to what is needed suitable for color high quality images if quality is set to high very portable, supported by almost everything that can display pictures compatibility with almost every image processing software  Cons:  high compression can lead to the image becoming blocky due to the way jpeg is compressed Every step of compression degrades the file Does not support transparency JPEG compression algorithm is a lossy compression format JPEG only supports 8bit images  You can use ImageResizer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Optimize Images for Web</title>
      <link>https://imageresizer.online/blog/posts/how-to-optimize-images-for-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 13:23:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imageresizer.online/blog/posts/how-to-optimize-images-for-web/</guid>
      <description>If you own a website and you are not resizing your image in terms of file size then I have some bad news for you, large images slow down your websites loading times.
There are some scary numbers with regards to slow websites, here are some of the numbers: Data from KISS Metrics - 1 second delay could lead to a 7% reduction in conversion - 47% of customers expect a page to load in 2 seconds or less - 40% of people abandon a website that takes longer than 3 seconds to load</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to resize photos for email attachments</title>
      <link>https://imageresizer.online/blog/posts/how-to-resize-photos-for-email-attachments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 19:47:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imageresizer.online/blog/posts/how-to-resize-photos-for-email-attachments/</guid>
      <description>When sending emails it is better for you and the recipient/s to send and receive images that have been resized.
If you try and send a large image it can take a long time for the email to send and when the recipients receive the email it can take a long time for them to download. Not to mention that some email providers have limits on the size of the attachments that you can send and receive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>